Our last major task is to implement some functionality inside of our MCP client
and allow us to list out all the different prompts that are defined inside the MCP server
and also get a particular prompt with some variables interpolated into it.
So let's first implement list prompts. I will delete the comment and replace it with a
result is await self session list prompts and then I will return result dot prompts
and that's pretty much it and then get prompt now to be clear when we get a individual prompt
we're going to be given some number of arguments these arguments will eventually show up inside of
our prompt function so for example inside a format document right here we expect to receive a document
id inside of this args dictionary the expectation is that there will be a document id key and that
will be passed in to the appropriate function over here and then we will get that value interpolated
into the prompt itself so inside the get prompt function I will get a result from self session
get prompt I'm going to pass in the prompt name that's the name of the prompt I want to retrieve
and then I'll pass in the arguments and then I will return result dot messages so those are the
messages coming back they form some kind of conversation that we want to feed directly into
clod and that's it that's all we have to do for our client so now we can test this out inside of
the cli itself I'll flip back over run the project again and now if I put in a slash right here I'll
see that I can access this format command now format is really just the name of the prompt
that we're going to invoke so if I select that and then hit space I'll then be asked to select one of
the different documents maybe I'll go with plan.md I'll hit enter and then we're taking that entire
prompt really just that single user message and feeding it directly into clod so clod now has the
instructions to go and reformat a document into markdown syntax and it has also been given the
id of the document that we want to reformat so the first thing it needs to do here is go and fetch
that document's contents and it will do so by using the git document tool and then finally clod is
going to respond with the markdown version of this document so here is the document with a bunch of
markdown syntax inside of it all right since it looked like this worked just fine let's do a quick
recap on prompts and make sure we understand what they are all about we begin by writing out and
evaluating a prompt that has some relevancy to our mcp server's purpose in our case we were making a
document server so having some functionality or something about rewriting a document in a different
style I think it kind of makes sense once we have put our prompt together we'll define a prompt inside
the mcp server and then our client can ask for that prompt at any point in time when we ask for
the prompt we will put in some number of arguments that will be provided to this prompting function
right here as keyword arguments and then our function can make use of those keyword arguments
inside the prompt itself